Roy J. Ingham Papers
Roy J. Ingham Papers
1944-1977
Ingham, Roy John, 1925-
1.25 linear ft.
Papers of the adult educator, Florida State University. Papers include speeches, surveys and reports, in addition to some publications, primarily abstracts and bibliographies.
149435
Biographical History
Roy J. Ingham was an American adult education scholar and teacher. He taught at the University of Chicago while earning his doctorate from that institution, served as Program Advisor at Syracuse University's University College, and was for many years a faculty member of the Florida State University Adult Education program.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Roy J. Ingham Papers is composed primarily of papers (surveys and reports) and publications (including a number of abstracts and bibliographies) collected by Ingham, the bulk dated 1961-1972. Most of the material reflects Ingham's interest in university adult education. A large portion deals with research into and theory of the nature of adult learning, both in general and in higher education settings.
The material is divided into five series. Professional work consists of two surveys of graduate programs in adult education. University adult education contains addresses, bibliographies, papers, and reports as well as information on the Antigonish Movement and on Florida State University degree programs. General theory and research includes books, abstracts, papers, and reports on adult literacy and adult learning. Organizations comprises correspondence and other material relating to various adult education organizations, including the Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC), Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA), the Fund for Adult Education (FAE), and the National Association of Public School Adult Educators (NAPSAE). A small amount of Miscellaneous material completes the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Related Material
holds a large number of collections relating to adult education, both of individuals and organizations. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
A large number of pamphlets were removed from the collection and transferred to the Adult Education Pamphlets Collection. Other pamphlets were duplicates of material already found in the general collection of E.S. Bird Library (listed at the end of this inventory), or in other adult education collections.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Ingham, Roy John, 1925- Archives.; Adult education.; Educators, United States.; Reports.; Speeches (documents); Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Professional work
  - "A survey of graduate programs in adult education in the U.S. and Canada", 1968; 1970 (Box 1)
  - Survey of graduate programs, 1977; correspondence, outline, form (Box 1)
- University adult education
  - Addresses
    - Graduate extension education, 1958 (Box 1)
    - "The role of the university in social change", 1965 (Box 1)
  - Antigonish movement, 1944-1969 (Box 1)
  - Bibliography: "University adult education: a selected bibliography" by Roger and Karen DeCrow, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Instructional techniques, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Florida State University, Division of Instructional Research, newsletter, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Degree programs
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Directory and analysis - Griffith and Cloutier, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Organizational patterns of programs, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Rollins College survey, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Papers
    - "The idea of the urban extension service", undated (Box 1)
    - Reprints, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Carnegie Commission report, 1971 (Box 1)
    - "The evening faculty", 1964 (Box 1)
    - "Factors associated with the achievement of adult students", 1964 (Box 2)
    - "Problems in administering general university extension programs", 1967 (Box 2)
- General theory and research
  - Abstracts: Knox et al
    - "Adult learning", 1961 (Box 2)
    - "Adult life cycle", 1962 (Box 2)
    - "Adult participation", 1961 (Box 2)
  - Book excerpt: Human communication, undated
  - Papers
    - Adult learning: Review of studies, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Psychological backgrounds of adult education, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Teacher behavior, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Toward a model of lifelong learning (Malcolm Knowles), 1972 (Box 2)
  - Participation, undated (Box 2)
  - Report: The pursuit of excellence, 1958 (Box 2)
- Organizations
  - Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 2)
    - "From the Dean's Desk", 1965-1969 (Box 2)
    - Report - Liveright; paper, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Center for the Study of Evaluation, 1960s; publication list (Box 2)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA), 1960; programming (Box 2)
  - Florida State Department of Education, 1976; "Competencies of adult educators" (Box 3)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE), 1958-1961; proposal, report (Box 3)
  - National Association of Public School Adult Educators (NAPSEA), 1969; report (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous
  - Community education/development, 1954-1971 (Box 3)
  - Florida Ten Million, Alfred North Whitehead, 1973? (Box 3)
  - Group discussion bibliography, undated (Box 3)
  - Planning for continuing education, 1971; remarks (Box 3)
  - Public school adult education, 1949; 1960 (Box 3)
  - Report: "Financing adult education in America's public schools and community councils", undated (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation. Urban extension: A report on experimental programs. New York: Ford Foundation, 1966; Transferred to general collection for cataloging.
  - Fund for Adult Education. The ten-year report, 1951-1961. New York: Fund for Adult Education, undated; Transferred to general collection for cataloging.
  - McMahon, Ernest E. Evening college: The second big chance. New York: Public Affairs Committee, 1968; Transferred to general collection for cataloging.
  - National Advisory Council on Adult Education (NACAE). Annual report. Washington, D.C.: National Advisory Council on Adult Education, 1972; Transferred to general collection for cataloging.
  - United States. The President's Committee on Education Beyond the High School. First interim report to the President. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1956; Transferred to general collection for cataloging.